# <u>Habibur Rahman</u>

+8801994688976 mdhabiburrb@gmail.com

https://hr-bappy.github.io/hr\_bappy

Frontend Developer: Seasoned and independent Front-End Developer with about 3 years of experience in blending the art of design with skill of programming using HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript with TDD unit testing: plus, modem libraries and frameworks such as ReactJS, NextJS as well as NodeJS to building and maintaining responsive websites with maintaining design pattern principles such as SOLID in the recruiting industry.



# **Experience**

12/2022 to Present

## Frontend Engineer

SWAP BD Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Build swap marketplace (e-commerce) website with the help of NextJs.
- Design admin panel and POS system swing ReactJs.
- Build supershop system using ReactJs, NodeJs, and mongoDB, that allow to publish products to multiple marketplace (Daraz, swap).

05/2022 to 11/2022

# Frontend Developer (ReactJs) WebX Global Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Develop e-commerce website builder (CMS) system using ReactJs that allow to design own website within 2 minutes.
- Designed the landing page using NestJs with SEO friendly.

03/2021 to 02/2022

## **Frontend Developer**

Shafa Care, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Designed telemedicine website and ShafaDev static website using NextJS.
- Build web-based video calling system using agora.io with NextJS.
- Developed ShafaCare admin dashboard using ReactJS and REST API

## **KEY SKILLS**

#### Languages:

HTML CSS

JAVASCRIPT TYPESCRIPT

#### Libraries:

ReactJs

**NextJs** 

React-Redux

NodeJs

**SCSS** 

#### CI/CD:

Git

#### **Management Tools:**

Trello

Jira

## **Education**

#### BSC in CSE:

International University of Business Agriculture and Technology 2017 to 2020 With CGPA: 3.73 out of 4

### **Activities**

- Competitive Programming
- Solving Problem (Math/IQ)
- Traveling

09/2020 to 03/2021

#### Jr. Front-End Developer + Intern Halcyon BD Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Designed 2 websites using ReactJs.
- Responsible for maintaining website and deploy on the server.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript to create 100+ responsive landing pages for both company and client using HTML CSS and JS according to PSD file.

# **Projects**

- SWAP Marketplace: NextJs, React-Redux, Server side rendering, SCSS, Bootstrap, TypeScript. <a href="https://swap.com.bd/">https://swap.com.bd/</a>
- Dealdone Supershop: ReactJs, React-Redux, Bootstrap, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB.
- WebX Global: E-Commerces website builder.
   ReactJs, React-Redux, NextJs (for Landing page),
   SCSS, TypeScript.
   <a href="https://webx.xyz">https://webx.xyz</a>
- Shafa Care: Telemedicine web app with web-based video calling system. NextJs, ReactJs, NodeJs, agora.ai
- **HalcyonBD:** ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PSD to HTML.

https://enrichgrp.com/ https://www.halcyonbd.com/

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Problem Solving:**

- Solved more than 1000 problems in different online judge
- Participate different Math IQ test

#### **Competitive Programming:**

- Attended 2 times NCPC in 2018 and 2020 Hosted by IUBAT and SUST
- Participate more than 12
   National and Inter University
   Programming Contest and got
   Certificate
- Attend Google Hash Code Programming Contest in 2020

### VOLUNTEERING

- Mentor of intermediate and beginner session of IUBAT Programming club
- Based on competitive programming arranged different seminar such as: weekly programming session, monthly programming contest.
- Help students for academic courses and projects

## REFERENCES

Dr. Utpal Kanti Das

Professor & Chairman, Department of CSE (IUBAT)

Email: ukd@iubat.edu

Md. Tanbir Hossen

Heed of Technology at SWAP Ltd.

Phone: +8801681445143

**SIGNATURE** 

Habibur Rahman

Habibur Rahman